Portfolio | Itch.io | Linkedin

About

I am an analytically inclined game designer and UI/UX designer forged from a lifetime of both teaching and learning in a wide variety of environments. I possess a diverse background in verbal and written communication, mobile and web development, documentation, working in and leading teams, prototyping, and providing and receiving feedback. Copious experience mastering a wide variety of games across every genre.

Technical Skills

Adobe Creative Suite • Blender • C++ • CSS • Figma • High fidelity mockups • HTML • InVision • Microsoft Office Suite • SAAS • Unreal Engine 4 • Visual Studio • Wireframing

Relevant Project Experience

Iron, Silver, and Salt — Podcast website

View Project

- Collaborated with shareholders and senior designers to create an interactive consumer experience for ongoing podcast.
- Anticipated problems and proactively solved them.
 - Designed solutions for episode descriptions that did not fit within the original boundaries.
- Conducted research to create the most comprehensive and streamlined experience for consumers.
- Collaborated with podcast hosts to deliver the desired systems and features.
- Lead effort to expand Iron, Silver, and Salt's branding by developing a style guide.

3D Portfolio Experience — Interactive portfolio

View Project

- Managed assets, source control, and scheduling to ensure project deadlines are met.
- Designed a virtual experience to present projects to potential consumers.
- Designed and developed all assets using Unreal Engine 4 and Blender.
- Scripted all necessary functionality for general consumption using UE4 Blueprint.
- Condensed all portfolio information to be more consumable within the interactive format.

Warna — Puzzle/Platformer

View Project

- Designed and implemented main menu, pause menu, and victory screen.
- Programmed all in-game functionality using UE4 blueprinting.
- Tested all aspects of gameplay, prioritizing and resolving bugs where time allowed.
- Created assets for use in-game, maintaining a consistent visual style throughout.
- Created store page in itch.io, providing information about the game and its development.

Job Experience

Mark Elrod

melrod8@gmail.com

Portfolio | Itch.io | Linkedin

Technical Writer — Technical Writers Inc

Jan 2015 - May 2019

- Acquired subject knowledge by interviewing departments/product developers.
- Ensured that all writings passed the required level of quality and effectiveness for the client's technical manuals.
- Developed and maintained high-quality documentation including user guides, online help, administration guides, and installation guides.
- Improved user experience by suggesting improvements to new features and workflows.
- Broke down complex technical subjects and presented them in an approachable way.
- Balanced stakeholders' needs and wants, resolving conflicts of opinion where necessary.
- Collaborated with graphic designers to create visual aids to assist users in understanding a product or process.

Intern, Data Analyst — PJM Interconnection

Jun 2013 – Aug 2013

- Assisted efforts to coordinate the production and distribution of electricity in 14 states.
- Created macros in Excel to assist interpreting the data provided by wind farms.
- Created databases for wind power generation classification, and power plant registry sorting.
- Used Access, VBA, and SQL to compile and verify information on generation units.

Emergency Medical Responder — Uwchlan Ambulance Corps

Jun 2011 – Feb 2013

- Maintained station, vehicles, and equipment, and performed inventory on ambulances.
- Responded to emergencies, aiding in patient diagnosis and treatment; determined the best method of treatment and transport for patients suffering from a wide variety of ailments.
- Participated as part of on-site emergency medical personnel at several events such as concert events, sporting events, and state fairs.

Education

Bloc – Designer Track

April 2020

Graduate, UI/UX Design

University of Delaware

May 2014

BS Mechanical Engineering, Mathematics, Biomechanical Engineering minors

Member: Marching band, Fencing club, Video game club